directed by Brigadier General Leslie
Groves he would work alongside the
physicist J Robert Oppenheimer in Los
Alamos New Mexico with the pair
beginning the race to build the world's
first nuclear weapon operating in 37
different facilities across the United
States and Canada and employing nearly
130,000 people the project would cost
over $2 billion in total amounting to
nearly 1% of the United States entire
defense spending during the war after
any 3 years of work Oppenheimer and his
team had done the impossible and they
were now ready to test launch the
world's first ever nuclear bomb set to
take place in the open desert plains of
New Mexico Oppenheimer would name the
event Trinity with over 400 people
coming to witness the dawn of a new age
and so in the early hours of July 16th
1945 the goahead to detonate the bomb
was given